RANJIT SAINI

(951) 216-9165 • rsaini88@gmail.com • Ranjit Saini LinkedIn

MANAGEMENT, SALES, AND OPERATIONS

I am an outcome-driven experienced and versatile sales and operations manager with over ten years of experience in leadership, operations management, consultative sales, and business development. Focused on building and retaining teams that deliver high levels results.

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

\checkmark	Project Management	\checkmark	Leadership	\checkmark	Reporting & Analysis
\checkmark	Business Development	\checkmark	Customer Retention	\checkmark	International Business
\checkmark	Sales & Marketing	\checkmark	Customer Service	\checkmark	Logistics

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

ReadySpaces Management LLC.

2019-Present

General Manager (GM) - Santa Ana, CA (2019-2022)

As a GM for ReadySpaces, my key role is to oversee the daily operations of a coworking warehouse and operate in a manner that aligns with the mission and vision of the organization. As customer facing and the primary liaison, I focus on understanding the needs of my clients and provide solutions to their needs.

- Recognized in the top three performers two years in a row and awarded rookie of the year.
- Received a Peer-to-Peer award in my second year in the company.
- Successfully launched the warehouse in La Mirada and Santa Ana and reached 100% capacity in both facilities before the target date.
- Implemented security projects company wide.
- Work closely with the VP of operation on streamlining company processes and creating operational policies.
- Create a team environment to ensure territory performance at the optimum level.
- First point of contact for all Customer escalations.
- Partner with each team member to identify operational gaps and risks and develop improvement plans to attain individual and company goals.

SRS Wireless, LLC - Palos Verdes, CA

2016 - 2019

Owner and Managing Partner

I had decided to open two of my own third-party retail Verizon wireless stores. Put in all the groundwork to open and operate the stores. As an owner operator, wore multiple hats to ensure proper operation of the business.

- Ran marketing events year around to create a presence in the community.
- Recruited, hired, and trained Managers and customer sales agents to deliver exceptional customer service.
- Forecasted sales to maintain proper inventory levels and proper cash flow.
- Work with employees to increase overall store profitability.
- Coached and trained employees to increase overall store profitability.
- Established relationships with the Chamber of Commerce and local businesses to promote and grow stores.

We R Wireless - Long Beach, CA

2014 - 2016

Store Manager

Managed a team of five sales representatives responsible for selling Verizon products and services.

- Induced an average of 15% growth in 6 months and aim to achieve 18% by end of 2015.
- Primary liaison for current and prospective clients; responsible for generating leads and closing sales.
- Conduct meetings to set monthly performance goals based on monthly quota.

Amprapur Overseas, Inc. - Garden Grove, CA

2013 - 2014

Sales Executive

Cultivated and managed relationships with e-commerce retailers to increase sales within the Textile, kitchen, and electronics industry.

- Interacted with customer management personnel to identify customer needs based on season and forecast textile sales accordingly.
- Hosted market events semiannually to identify trends and present upcoming designs.
- Increased sales with Zulily.com by 60% in five months with a continuous upward trend.

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

Staples Business Advantage - La Mirada, CA 2012 to 2013 WW Grainger - Temecula, CA 2011 to 2012 Ikon Office Solutions - Redlands, CA 2010-2011

EDUCATION

B.S., Business Administration
California Polytechnic University, Pomona CA
Project Management Institute